MARCUS EVERSON

Phoenix, AZ

480 695-5728 · mreverson91@gmail.com Github Portfolio

Marcus Everson is an experienced full stack developer for web and mobile applications with a love for a functional front end. He has created and developed a wide range of applications across multiple industries. Team members can expect strong communication, organization, and a willingness to accomplish the collective goal. When not working at his desk, Marcus enjoys collaborating with friends on digital arts projects and traveling to local coffee shops with his dog.

SKILLS

_			
•	Languages: JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS	•	API: REST
•	Frameworks: React, Redux, KeystoneJS,	•	Database: MongoDB, Firebase, PostgreSQL
	EmberJS		
•	Platforms: AWS		

EXPERIENCE

March 2020 - Present

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FREELANCE

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

- Developed front-facing site and internal tools for nationwide fintech company
- SPA for mid-sized catering and food service company
- MVP for app to invite and schedule group meetups
- Developed an online dynamic testing platform using Ember
- Internal client and file management portal for mid-sized national accounting firm

Technologies Used: EmberJS, React, Node, JavaScript, KeystoneJS

JUNE 2018 - 2020

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ALTRA MORTGAGE CAPITAL, LLC

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

- Created multiple React SaaS applications
- Created custom CRM used to send thousands of daily marketing emails
- Led Testing and QA for all custom business applications

BACK END DEVELOPMENT

- Developed REST API endpoints for all platform utilities & components
- Architected SQL DB and business user reporting

Technologies Used: React, Node, JavaScript, Python, AWS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Go

AUGUST **2017** – **2018**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, THELEADGROUP.COM

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

- Created customer facing website using Bootstrap
- Created internal email marketing tools using KeystoneJS
- Developed process for email templating and testing

Technologies Used: Node, Keystone, JavaScript, AWS, MongoDB

JANUARY 2016 - 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CAPITAL ACCOUNTING, PC

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

- Created customer facing website using Bootstrap
- Migrated existing site to Keystone

Technologies Used: Node Keystone, JavaScript, AWS, MongoDB

EDUCATION

May 2015

COMPUTER INFORMATICS, ARIZONA STATE UNIVERSITY